Guide to the Kenneth E. Bailey Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Correspondence, Series II
  - Regarding Theological Education in the Middle East
    - "1. Paper Files Index, 2. Directory for Shenango Presbytery, 3. Stop Watch Instructions, 4. Contents of C.V. Files" (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - "Theological Review - NEST" (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - General / Misc. Correspondence
    - "Papers, Correspondence 1960-1970" (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - "Correspondence 1964, 1998, 2001" (Box 17, Folder 2)
      Misc. correspondence: Christmas with the Ken Baileys, Assuit Egypt, 1964; Hilda, Tom, and Anne; notes on Arabic translations of Gospels
    - "Correspondence 1966, 1976-78, 1980" (Box 17, Folder 3)
      Misc. correspondence
    - "Correspondence 1965, 1970, 1978-1979, 1996-2004" (1) (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - "Correspondence 1965, 1970, 1978-1979, 1996-2004" (2) (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - "Correspondence 1971-1972" (Box 17, Folder 6)
      Beulah United Presbyterian System, Near East School of Theology
    - "Papers & Articles - 1971, 1995, 2010" (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - "Correspondence 1967, 1975-77, 81-83" (1) (Box 17, Folder 8)
      United Presbyterian Church in the United States of America; misc.
    - "Correspondence 1967, 1975-77, 81-83" (2) (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - "Misc. Correspondece 1980-1992" (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - "Correspondence 1981-1982" (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - "Personal Letters 1981-1983 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - "Correspondence, Articles, Reflections 1981-1986" (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - "Correspondence 1982-1988 (also 1978)" (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - "Correspondence 1982-1989" (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - "Correspondence 1983-1984" (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - "Correspondence 1983-1985" (1) (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - "Correspondence 1983-1985" (2) (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - "Memorable Correspondence 1980-1990" (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - "General Correspondence 1984, 1987-1988, 1991-1994" (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - "General Correspondence 1980, 1985-1990" (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - "General Correspondence 1982-1986 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - "General Correspondence 1985-1990; 1975-1976" (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - "General Correspondence 1991-1992; 1970-1972 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - "General Correspondence 1986-1987" (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - "Correspondence 1985-1995" (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - "1987-1994 Correspondence" (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - "Correspondence 1988-1991" (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - "Miscellaneous Correspondence 1988-1995" (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - "E.J. Brill 1989-1990" (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - "General Correspondence 1989-2000 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - "General Correspondence 1990-1993" (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - "Correspondence 1990-1994" (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - "Personal Papers 1985-1990" (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - "1991-1995 Correspondence" (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - "1992-1995 Correspondence" (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - "Correspondence 1994-1997" (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - "General Correspondence 1995-2001" (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - "Correspondence 1996-1998" (1) (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - "Papers & Correspondence 1997 (also 1967)" (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - "Correspondence 1996-1998 (also 1961)" (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - "1999 Selected" (1) (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - "1999 Selected" (2) (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - "1997, 1999, 2001-2002 Correspondence" (1) (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - "1997, 1999, 2001-2002 Correspondence" (2) (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - "Lohses Furlag 2000-2001" (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - "General Correspondence 2001, 2004, 2005" (1) (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - "General Correspondence 2001, 2004, 2005" (2) (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - "Correspondence 2001-2008" (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - "Kathy Strieter, Artist, 2002" (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - "General Correspondence 2001, 2008-2009" (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - "Letters 2003" (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - "Episcopal Diocese of Pittsburgh 2003; Anglican 2005" (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - "General Correspondence 2003-2007 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - "Correspondence 2004-2008" (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - "General Correspondence 2005, 2012" (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - "Valuable Papers 2004-2005" (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - "Articles & Papers 2005-2007" (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - "Speaking Invitation Declined 2005-2007" (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - "Correspondence 2006-2008" (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - "Papers & Articles 2007-2008" (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - "Correspondence 2008, 2009, 2010" (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - "Correspondence 2009" (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - "Papers & Articles 2009" (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - "Correspondence 2010, 2011, 2012" (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - "Correspondence 2010-2011" (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - "Miscellaneous Correspondence 2010-2012; Lessons 1-12" (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - "Correspondence 2011-2012" (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - "Paper & Articles 2011-2012" (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - "Correspondence 2012-2013" (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - "Papers & Articles 2011-2013" (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - "Miscellaneous Articles, Letters, Genealogy 1993, 1994, 2010, 2013, 2016" (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - "General Correspondence 2015-2016" (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - "Dawson-Bailey 1996-2000" (1) (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - "Dawson-Bailey 1996-2000" (2) (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - "Dawson-Bailey 2001-2003" (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - "Dawson-Bailey 2004-2009" (1) (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - "Dawson-Bailey 2004-2009" (2) (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - "Dawson-Bailey 2011-2014" (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - "Dawson-Bailey 2010-2016" (1) (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - "Dawson-Bailey 2010-2016" (2) (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - "Miscellaneous Correspondence 2015-2016 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Family correspondence and papers
    - Family Correspondence (1) (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Family Correspondence (2) (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Family Correspondence (3) (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Family Correspondence (4) (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Family Correspondence (5) (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Family Correspondence (6) (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Family Correspondence (7) (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Family Correspondence (8) (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Family Correspondence (9) (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Family Correspondence (10) (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Family Correspondence (11) (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Family Correspondence (12) (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Family Correspondence (13) (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Family Correspondence (14) (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Family Correspondence (15) (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Famil Correspondence (16) (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Family Correspondence (17) (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Family Correspondence (18) (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - "Documents & Jewelry" (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - "Schultz School" (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - "Family Tree & History" (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - "Bailey Family History" (1) (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - "Bailey Family History" (2) (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - "Family History (Special Papers) 1982-1996" (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - "David's Letters (Beirut)" (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - "Kenneth's Letters" (1) (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - "Kenneth's Letters" (2) (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - "Biographical / Memoir" (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - "Sara & Victor" (Box 29, Folder 4)
- Biblical Scholarship Resources, Series III
  - "Genesis & Old Testament Theology" (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - "Psalms" (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - "Ezekiel - Psalms - Amos - Prophets (Miscellaneous)" (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - "Hosea" (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - "Hosea 7:1-14:9" (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - "Amos" (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - "Habakkuk" (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - "Matthew 1:1-6:34" (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - "Matthew 7:1-25:13" (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - "Studies in Matthew" (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - "Mark" (1) (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - "Mark" (2) (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - "Mark" (3) (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - "Mark" (4) (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - "Mark" (5) (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - "Mark 6:1-16:8" (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - "The Text of the Gospel According to Mark" (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - "Luke" (1) (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - "Luke - 6:39" (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - "Luke - 9:51" (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - "Luke 10:2-12:59" (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - "Luke 13:1-1525b" (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - "Luke 16:1-17:37" (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - "Luke 19:11-19:24" (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - "Rhetoric & Theology of Selected Passages in Luke" (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - "Rhetoric & Theology of Selected Passages in Luke - Study Guide" (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - "John 1:1-5:47" (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - "John 6:1-20" (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - "John 7-21" (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - "John Parables" (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - "Acts 1:1-2:47" (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - "Acts 3:12-7:60" (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - "Acts 28:28" (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - "Romans" (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - "I Corinthians 1:1-10:33" (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - "I Corinthians 4:17-7:40" (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - "I Corinthians 11:1-15:58" (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - "I Corinthians" Miscellaneous (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - "Galatians" (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - "Ephesians" (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - "Philippians" (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - "Colossians" (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - "I-II Timothy" (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - "Hebrews 1:1-10:39" (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - "Hebrews 11:1-13:25" (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - "James" (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - "I Peter" (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - "I John, II John, III John" (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - "Revelation" (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - "Parables Intro. 1-5" (1) (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - "Parables Intro. 1-5" (2) (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - "Parables 6-14" (1) (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - "Parables 6-14" (2) (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - "New Books of Articles" (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - "Women in New Testament" (1) (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - "Women in New Testament" (2) (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - "Women in New Testament" (3) (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - "Women in the New Testament II" (1) (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - "Women in the New Testament II" (2) (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - "Parables II" (1) (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - "Parables II" (2) (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - "New Testament Culture" (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - "I Corinthians: Its Rhetoric and Culture" (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - "I Corinthians: Its Rhetoric and Culture" (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - "I Corinthians: Its Rhetoric and Culture" (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - "I Corinthians: Its Rhetoric and Culture" (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - "Rhetorical Commentary on Isaiah 46-66 and I Corinthians" (1) (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - "Rhetorical Commentary on Isaiah 46-66 and I Corinthians" (2) (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - "Isaiah 40:1-53:13" (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - "Isaiah 54:1-66:24" (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - "New Testament Poet Masters Acts - Romans" (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - "New Testament Poet Masters I Corinthians - Revelation (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - "Arch 1995" (1) (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - "Arch 1995" (2) (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - "Mandate for the Nations | Light out of Darkness" (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - "Jesus and the Reprocessing of Anger into Grace | Parable of Two Lost Sons | Jesus Interprets His Cross" (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - "Leadership in the New Testament" (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - "Paul Through Mediterranean Eyes: Cultural Studies in I Corinthians" (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - "Paul Through Mediterranean Eyes Study Sheets" (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Dialogue with Jeremiah and Yahua" (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - "'The Good Shepherd' A Theological Journey of a Thousand Years Study Sheets" (Box 39, Folder 6)
- Writings, Series IV
  - Articles, sermons, and lectures
    For an overview of published articles by Bailey see the chronologically arranged printouts of articles compiled by New Testament scholar Dale Bowne in Box 64.
    - "Current Writing and Lectures" (1) (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - "Current Writing and Lectures" (2) (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - "Oral Traditions" (1) (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - "Oral Traditions" (2) (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - "Misc. Lectures Vol. 2" (1) (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - "Misc. Lectures Vol. 2" (2) (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - "Misc. Lectures Vol. 2" (3) (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - "Mapping Mission as Translation with Reference to Michael Polanyi's Heuristic Philosophy - ETSC Richard Haney" (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - "Jesus Interprets His Cross; Atonement; Christology" (1) (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - "Jesus Interprets His Cross; Atonement; Christology" (2) (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - "Languages" (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - "Birth Stories" (1) (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - "Birth Stories" (2) (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - "Hermeneutics Christianity" (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - "Lectures - Middle East" (1) (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - "Lectures - Middle East" (2) (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - "Kenneth Bailey - Sermons" (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - "Kenneth Bailey - Personal Lectures" (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - "Personal Articles Volume 1" (1) (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - "Personal Articles Volume 1" (2) (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - "Personal Articles Volume 2" (1) (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - "Personal Articles Volume 2" (2) (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - "Personal Articles Volume 3" (1) (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - "Personal Articles Volume 3" (2) (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - "Personal Articles Volume 3" (3) (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - "Personal Articles Volume 4" (1) (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - "Personal Articles Volume 4" (2) (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - "Personal Articles Volume 4" (3) (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - "Sermons" (1) (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - "Sermons" (2) (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - "Sermons - English" (1) (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - "Sermons - English" (2) (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - "Sermons - English" (3) (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - "Sermons 2015" (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - "Sermons and Miscellaneous" (1) (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - "Sermons and Miscellaneous" (2) (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - "Miscellaneous Bible Lectures Heard" (1) (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - "Miscellaneous Bible Lectures Heard" (2) (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - "Miscellaneous Lectures - Biblical Interpretation" (1) (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - "Miscellaneous Lectures - Biblical Interpretation" (2) (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - "Articles Vol. 2" (1) (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - "Articles Vol. 2" (2) (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - "Articles 1992 - Book Articles Read" (1) (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - "Articles 1992 - Book Articles Read" (2) (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - "Articles 1993" (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - "Articles 1994" (1) (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - "Articles 1994" (2) (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - "Extra Papers - 1995" (1) (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - "Extra Papers - 1995" (2) (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - "1996 Articles & Papers Clipped" (1) (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - "1996 Articles & Papers Clipped" (2) (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - "Letters, Saved Papers, Clippings - Qadar - 2002-2003 | American Mission Centennial 1954 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - "MEC & Gospel and our Culture 1992 & 1993" (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - "Jean Porter - Parables" (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - "A Pilgrimage to the Holy Land (2 copies)" (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - "Theology of Mission" (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - "Luke 15 - Jesus as Theologian" (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - "Jesus as Theologian" (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - "New Testament Middle East Exegesis" (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - "New Books" (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - "Bible & Quran" (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - "Islam - Hassan & Noor" (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - "Ibn al Asal" (1) (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - "Ibn al Asal" (2) (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - "Ibn al Asal" (3) (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - "Jesus Through Middle Eastern Eyes: Arabic" (1) (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - "Jesus Through Middle Eastern Eyes: Arabic" (2) (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - "Arabic - Jesus Through Middle Eastern Eyes" (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - "Arabic Versions" (1) (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - "Arabic Versions" (2) (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - "The Mission and Death of Jesus in Islam and Christianity; A.H. Mathias Zohniser (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - "Brown, R. 'Allegory Reconsidered'; Torrey, C.C. 'The Second Isaiah'" (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - "Brown, R. 'Roles of Women in the Fourth Gospel'" (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Brown, R. 'Parables & Allegory Reconsidered" (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - "Brown, R. 'The Meaning of Modern New Testament Studies for an Ecumenical Understanding of Mary'" (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - "Streeter, 'Poems of Jesus'" (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - "Review of Lund" (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - "Lectures Heard - Personal Reflections (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - "Miscellaneous" (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - "Miscellaneous - 2000 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - "Ken Bailey - Miscellaneous" (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - "Memorial Service, etc." (Box 49, Folder 13)
    - "The Parables of Jesus in Luke: A Middle Eastern View" - study guide for sessions at Maryknoll Mission Institute, 2012 (Box 49, Folder 14)
    - Printouts of articles by Bailey, compiled by New Testament scholar Dale Bowne, 1972-2001 (Box 64, Folder 1-19)
  - Miscellaneous writings and papers
    - "Good Shepherd Review" (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - "Reviews: Jesus Through Middle Eastern Eyes" (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - "Among the Ruins" (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - "Oral Tradition Rejoinder" (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - "New Testament Articles of Interest" (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - "Comments on Western Culture" (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - "De-Zionizing of the Tradition" (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - "History of Christianity in Arabia" (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - "Islam" (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - "Pharisees in the New Testament" (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - "Oxford: Bodleian Library" (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - "Nashotah House" (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - "Trinity Seminary Library" (Box 51, Folder 13)
    - "Biblical Literacy Task Force" (Box 51, Folder 14)
    - "Catholic Letters (General)" (Box 51, Folder 15)
    - "Diocese of Pittsburgh General" (Box 51, Folder 16)
    - "Anglican Diocese of Pittsburgh" (Box 51, Folder 17)
    - "Trinity Episcopal School for Ministry (TESM)" (Box 51, Folder 18)
    - "Cover Sheets for I Corinthians" (Box 51, Folder 19)
    - "Essays by Ken E. Bailey on Culture & Style" (Box 51, Folder 20)
    - "Ken E. Bailey Website (www.shenango.org/bailey.htm) (Box 51, Folder 21)
    - "Presbytery of Shenango" (Box 51, Folder 22)
    - "Declined Speaking 2016" (Box 51, Folder 23)
    - "Thanks for Gifts" (Box 51, Folder 24)
    - "Valuable Papers 2013" (Box 51, Folder 25)
    - "Acts 10" (Box 51, Folder 26)
    - "Archbishop Roger Herft" (Box 51, Folder 27)
    - "Rev. Stig-Olaf Fernstrom" (Box 51, Folder 28)
    - "LPUB/General" (Box 51, Folder 29)
    - "Bible Reading Fellowship" (Box 51, Folder 30)
    - "Fellowship of Faith for the Muslims" (Box 51, Folder 31)
    - "Hearts & Minds - Borger" (Box 51, Folder 32)
    - "Pittsburgh Theological Seminary Library" (Box 51, Folder 33)
    - "Keith Brown (Project)" (Box 51, Folder 34)
    - "Bethlehem - Diyar" (Box 51, Folder 35)
    - "Presbyterians for Faith, Family, and Ministry" (Box 51, Folder 36)
    - "ECO: A Covenant Order of Evangelical Presbyterians" (Box 51, Folder 37)
    - "Evangelicals for Middle East Understanding" (Box 51, Folder 38)
    - "Evangelicals for Middle East Understanding - New" (Box 51, Folder 39)
    - "Presbyterians for Renewal" (Box 51, Folder 40)
    - "Outreach Fundraising" (Box 51, Folder 41)
    - "SNTS - International Society for New Testament Studies" (Box 51, Folder 42)
    - "World Mission Initiative" (Box 51, Folder 43)
    - "Middle East Concern" (Box 51, Folder 44)
    - "Trinity - Stevenson - Good (with contract) Good Shepherd Recordings" (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - "Leadership in the New Testament Flyers" (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - "AV - Gregg Hartung" (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - "Film - The Prodigal" (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - "Pictures" (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - "Ken Bailey Personal Papers (& their future) (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - "Cairo Seminary" (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - "Sabeel" (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - "Chrysostom - Arabic" (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - "Evangelicals for Middle East Understanding - New" (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - "The Wintery Well" (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - "Ibn al-Tayyib" (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - "Jesus Through Middle Eastern Eyes" (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - "Ibn al Asal" (Box 52, Folder 14)
    - "DVD Study Sheet Correspondence" (Box 52, Folder 15)
    - "Distributions" (Box 52, Folder 16)
    - "Study Guides for DVD" (Box 52, Folder 17)
    - "Study Guides - Mission" (Box 52, Folder 18)
    - "I Corinthians Study Guide" (Box 52, Folder 19)
    - "Descriptions of Recorded Series (DVD General) (Box 52, Folder 20)
    - "DVD Description - Faith Narratives" (Box 52, Folder 21)
    - "Correspondence Friar Justin" (Box 52, Folder 22)
    - "Books in Print by Matta al Miskeen" (Box 52, Folder 23)
    - "Arabic Versions" (Box 52, Folder 24)
    - "Arabic Versions" (Box 52, Folder 25)
    - "New Music" (Box 52, Folder 26)
    - "The Nail - Play / Story" (Box 52, Folder 27)
    - "Prayers" (Box 52, Folder 28)
    - "Books (List - Kenneth E. Bailey" (Box 52, Folder 29)
    - "DVD Sheets" (Box 52, Folder 30)
    - "Drawings Completed - Copy #1" (Box 52, Folder 31)
    - "Arabic Calligraphy by Kenneth E. Bailey (NEST Years) (Box 52, Folder 32)
    - "Art Work - Bitar" (Box 52, Folder 33)
    - "Hibitallah - Staal" (Box 52, Folder 34)
    - "Eastern Spirituality Prayers, Etc." (Box 52, Folder 35)
    - "Drake Well Project" (Box 52, Folder 36)
    - "Episcopal Church 2006-2008" (Box 52, Folder 37)
    - "Papers" (Box 52, Folder 38)
    - "New Testament Committee Arcticles 1992-2003" (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - "Institute Papers 1974-1975" (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - "New Testament Institute at NEST Miscellaneous 1974-1981" (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - "Articles, Papers 1954-1984" (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - "Staal 1985-1986 - Matthew" (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - "Staal 1986 - Mark" (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - "Staal 1986 - Luke" (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - "Staal 1986a - John" (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - "Staal 1997-2000" (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - "Van Dyke - 1906" (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - "Papers - Jesus as Theologian 4 Letters" (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - "Miscellaneous Papers 1987-1990" (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - "Arabic Photo Copies" (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - "Papers, Articles 1984, etc." (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - "Week-at-a-Glance Calendars" (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous: Leather Notebook, Three Bibles (2 English, 1 Arabic), Passports (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Notes on the Bailey papers by David Dawson (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Plays, Poems, and Short Stories
    - "Eyes on the Cross" (1) (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - "Eyes on the Cross" (2) (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - "Plays & Poems by Ken Bailey" (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - "Plays: The Royal Sanctuary (2 copies); The First Supper; The Nail" (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - A Sheep, A Coin, and Two Sons (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - A Sheep, A Coin, and Two Sons (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - "The Summoning of Everyman" (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - "Personal Stories and Short Stories" (1) (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - "Personal Stories and Short Stories" (2) (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - "Stories by Kenneth E. Bailey" (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Books
    Additional books by Bailey that are held in the Library's cataloged collection include: Finding the lost: cultural keys to Luke 15, Jesus through Middle Eastern eyes: cultural studies in the Gospels, Paul through Mediterranean eyes: cultural studies in 1 Corinthians, Poet and peasant: a literary-cultural approach to the parables in Luke, Through peasant eyes: more Lucan parables, their culture and style
    - The Cross and the Prodigal: Luke 15 Through the Eyes of Middle Eastern Peasants (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - God Is… Dialogues On the Nature of God (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Jacob and the Prodigal: How Jesus Retold Israel's Story (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - The Good Shepherd: A Thousand-Year Journey from Psalm 23 to the New Testament (Box 62, Folder 5)
- Audio-Visual / Digital Material, Series V
  - Computer files
    - "File #1 Letters" (Box 57, Folder 1)
      Floppy Disks
    - "Book: Finding the Lost" (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - "Special Program (from David)" (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - "Tadros Back Ups" (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - "Letters Off-load" (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - "Unfinished Computer Filing 7/95" (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - "Letters Off-load" 2 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - "Miscellaneous Back Ups" (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - "Blank / Formatted" (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - "Extra Programs (David) and Habib's Dissertation" (Box 58, Folder 4)